A. Elizabeth Jennings Collection Ms B17
Fairfield Museum and History Center
A. Elizabeth Jennings Collection
1748-1970
Ms B17
Fairfield Museum and History Center
14.0 Linear feet (30 boxes, 3 oversize items, 5,500 items)
Collected by Fairfield resident Anne Elizabeth Jennings throughout her life, this collection contains papers of the Morehouse and Jennings families, otehr Fairfield families, the Fairfield First Church of Christ Congregational, Saint Paul's Episcopal Church and the Fairfield School District. A number of photographs of the Morehouse and Jennings families as well as areas around Fairfield are also included.
various
Drawer Map file, Drawer 9
Drawer Map File, Drawer 9
Conditions Governing Access note
There are no restrictions on access to this collection.
Biographical/Historical note
Anne Elizabeth Jennings (19 December 1893-21 April 1984) was unmarried and lived in Fairfield all her life. She went to Cortland School in Bridgeport and lived with her parents at the corner of Beach Rd. and Post Rd. until 1953 when she built her own house at 419 Beach Rd. She was a member and supporter of the DAR, Fairfield Garden Club, Fairfield Historical Society, First Church of Christ Congregational and other organizations. Her particular interests were travel, the theatre, architecture and recipes. She was descended from many of the original settlers of Fairfield (see genealogical chart for details).
Scope and Contents note
This collection consists of 35 boxes and 3 oversize items. The collection is divided into Morehouse family papers, Jennings family papers, other Fairfield family papers, Fairfield First Church of Christ Congregational papers, Saint Paul's Episcopal Church papers, Fairfield School District papers and photographs.
Boxes I through VII contain Morehouse family papers mostly belonging to Captain Samuel Morehouse, his son Samuel Morehouse, Jr., Angeline Morehouse and Anne O. Morehouse. Letters between Samuel and Angeline and Samuel and his daughter Anne make up a large part of the family papers.
The Jennings family make up Boxes VIII through XX. Abraham Gould Jennings' correspondence and Mary E. Bulkley's correspondence are in Boxes VIII through X. Isaac Jennings letters, journals, and sea logs are in Boxes X through XII. Boxes XIII through XV hold Charles B. Jennings' papers including his Yale school work. A. Elizabeth's papers are in Boxes XVI through XVIII and Jennings Brothers business related material is in Box XIX.
The middle part of the collection is made up of a box of genealogy (XX) and other families papers (XXI). Fairfield's First Church of Christ Congregational papers make up Boxes XXI through XXV and include bills, membership records and account books. Saint Paul's Episcopal Church is represented in Box XXVI.
Box XXVII holds Fairfield School District papers, mostly made up of reports and enumerations. The last Boxes, XXVIII through XXXV contain photographs of various families and places in Fairfield. Oversize items E and F are located in the Map file, Drawer 9.
Beers family; Bulkley family; Burr family; Burr, Angeline; First Church (Fairfield, Conn.). First Church Congregational.; Hyde family; Jennings Family; Jennings, Abraham Gould, 1781-1852; Jennings, Anne Elizabeth, 1893-1984; Jennings, Anne Elizabeth, 1893-1984; Jennings, Annie Burr, 1855-1939; Jennings, Charles Bulkley, 1865-1950; Jennings, Isaac, Capt.; Jennings, Mary E. Bulkley; Knapp family; Morehouse family; Morehouse, Anne O.; Morehouse, Samuel, Jr.; Morehouse, Samuel; Nichols family; Ogden family; Osborne family; Rye Female Seminary (Rye, N.Y.).; St. Paul's Episcopal Church (Fairfield, CT).; Sturgis family; Yale College (1718-1887) .; Account books--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Churches--Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Daughters of the American Revolution.; Deeds--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Fairfield(Conn.); Merchants--Connecticut--Fairfield.; Probate records--Connecticut--Fairfield; Receipts(financial records); School attendance; Schools--Connecticut.; Ships
- Box I: Samuel Morehouse (Capt.) and Samuel Morehouse Jr. papers, 1814-1906; 12 folders, 445 items; Folders C through L contain papers belonging to Samuel Morehouse, Jr.
  - Legal and financial papers (Capt. Morehouse), 1814-1832; Folder A; 18 items
  - Millplain School bills foudn with Capt. Morehouse papers, 1822-1828; Folder B; 5 items
  - Deeds, 1868-1887; Folder C; 8 items
  - Business papers, 1850-1860; Folder D; 50 items
  - Business papers, 1869-1880; Folder E; 20 items
  - Business papers, 1890-1899, 1902, n.d.; Folder F; 80 items
  - School and legal papers, 1858, 1864, 1879, 1895, n.d.; Folder G; 24 items
  - Bills of lading NY/NH and Hartford railroad, 1899-1902; Folder H; 63 items
  - Stamped envelopes to Samuel Morehouse, 1880-1899; Folder I; 48 items
  - Stamped envelopes to Samuel Morehouse, 1890-1909; Folder J; 66 items
  - Letters, 1851-1855; Folder K; 24 items
  - Letters, 1874-1906; Folder L; 39 items
- Box II: Letters to Samuel Morehouse from Angeline; NYC draft notice, 1855-1877; 7 folders, 175 items
  - Letters, 1860; Folder C; 23 items
  - Letters; NYC draft notice, 1861, 1863; Folder E; 32 items
- Box III: Letters to Angeline from Samuel Morehouse, 1855-1877; 16 folders, 485 items
- Box IV: Letters to Anna O. Morehouse from Samuel Morehouse, 1897-1904; 9 Folders, 263 items
  Other Finding Aids note
  More detailed description of letters can be found inside the Box.
- Box V: Letters to Anne O. Morehouse from Samuel Morehouse, 1905-1907; 6 folders, 196 items
  A more detailed description of each letter can be found inside the Box.
- Box VI: Anne O. Morehouse papers, 1875-1930; 8 folders, 172 items
  - Letters, 1875-1922; Folders A-C; 72 items
  - Letters to Rosemond, Illinois, 1912; Folder D; 18 items
  - Letters, 1925-1950; Folder E; 43 items
  - Letters from S. C. Morehouse, 1903-1917; Folder F; 20 items
  - Notebooks and DAR papers, 1929-1930; Folder G; 6 items
  - Miscellaneous notes and clippings, 1891, n.d.; Folder H; 13 items
    A more detailed description of items can be found inside the Box.
- Box VII: Morehouse assorted papers, 1790-1912; 9 folders, 148 items
  A detailed listing of items is available in the Box.
  - Letters to Angeline and/or Samuel Morehouse from Mary Morehouse, 1865-1878; Folder A; 20 items
  - Letters to Angeline, 1854-1877; Folder B; 40 items
  - Letters to S. Clinton Morehouse, 1877, 1905, 1912, n.d.; Folder C; 5 items
  - Elizabeth Morehouse and Mary O. Bulkley correspondence; miscellanneous correspondence, 1855-1870; Folder D; 9 items
  - Deeds, 1790-1793; Folder E; 3 items
    - David Gilbord from Seth Morehouse, 1790
    - David Judson from Abraham Morehouse, 1791, 1793
  - Wedding and calling cards and photos, Folder F; 25 items
  - Business cards, advertisements, school and church papers (New York), Golden Hill School for Boys (Bridgport) and Fairfield Beach Co. papers, Folder G; 33 items
  - Miscellaneous, Folder H; 12 items
  - Samuel Morehouse diary, 1853; Folder I
- Box VIII: A. G. Jennings, Sr. papers, letters and account books, 1808-1852; 17 folders
  - A. G. Jennings, Sr. correspondence, 1818-1850; Folders A-K
  - A. G. Jennings, Sr. day book and journal, 1808-1847; Folder L
  - A. G. Jennings, Sr. journal and chap book, 1835-1851; Folder M
  - Ship Saludas records (A. G. Jennings, Sr. Captain), 1826-1835; Folder N
  - Certificate from CT Washington Total Abstinence Society, receipt, copy of petition, 1841, 1834; Folder O; 3 items
  - Letters to Anna Burr Jennings, Folder P
  - Letter from A. G. Jennings, Jr., 1854; Folder Q
- Box IX: Mary E. Bulkley Jennings papers, 1854-1887; 10 folders, 217 items
  - Letters from Isaac Jennings, 1854-1864; Folders A-H; 96 items
  - Southport National Bank cancelled checks, 1883-1887; Folder I; 80 items
  - Stock transactions, 1871-1884; Folder J; 42 items
- Box X: Isaac Jennings papers, 1854-1886; 10 folders, 210 items
  - Letters from Mary E. Bulkley Jennings, 1854-1855; Folders A-D; 57 items
  - Incoming correspondence, 1858-1886; Folder E; 15 items
  - Letter from Isaac Jennings (uncle-in-law of John Pierson), 1839; Folder F
  - Bills and bills receipted, 1856-1886; Folders G & H; 106 items
  - Legal papers, 1856-1886; Folder I; 30 items
    - Will and estate inventory, 9 items
    - Deed from William H. and Mary A. Burr from Isaac Jennings, 1856
    - Deed from Augustus and A. G. Jennings to Isaac Jennings, 1856
    - Deed from Mallett Seeley to Augustus and Isaac Jennings, 1866, 1885; 2 items
    - Deed from Bennett A. Seeley to Augustus and Isaac Jennings, 1867
    - Deed from Isaac Jennings to Mary E. Jennings, 1879
    - Deed from Augustus Jennings to Isaac Jennings, 1885
    - Promissory note from Augustus and Isaac Jennings to Bennett Seeley, 1867
    - Consulate travel certificate, 1861
    - Texas and Pacific Railway co. brochure, 1886
    - Exhibitor's pass, International Exhibition, Philadelphia, 1876
  - Isaac Jennings' account book and religious tract, 1882-1885, n.d.; Folder J; 2 items
- Box XI: Isaac Jennings shipping papers, 1838-1863; 13 folders, 26 items
  - Jennings' sea journals and negative of Isaac Jennings, 1838-1850, 1850-1862; Folder A; 3 items
  - Papers from Jennings' journal, 1838-1850; Folder B; 1 item
  - Map from Jennings' journal, 1838-1850; Folder C
  - Jennings' journal (photocopy), 1838-1850; Folder D
  - Jennings' journal (photocopy), 1850-1852; Folder E
  - Jennings' abstract log, 1848-1855; Folder F
  - Jenning's account book with Chamberlain and Phelps, New York, 1848-1856; Folder G
  - Jennings' expense account book, 1850-1863; Folder H
  - Jennings' journal, 1861-1862; Folder I
  - Jennings' seaman's certificate (photo and negative), 1838; Folder J
  - Tables and books, Folder K
    - Jennings' traverse tables, 1852
    - A Short History of the Tower of London, 1852
    - Hampton Court Palace, 1852
    - New Sailing Directions for the Mediterranean Sea, 1847
  - Map of Sevilla, n.d.; Folder L
  - Jennings' shipping papers (misc.), 1862, n.d.; Folder M; 11 items
- Box XII: Jennings papers and miscellaneous, 1832-1903; 12 folders, 337 items
  - Letters to Mrs. Isaac Jennings, 1881-1903; Folders A & B; 19 items
  - Invitations, n.d.; Folders C & D; 84 items
  - Miscellaneous, Folder E
    - Papers re: David Burr Jennings, 23 items
    - Letters from D. B. Jennings, 1834, 1837-1838; 3 items
    - Letters to D. B. Jennings, 1836-1838, n.d.; 14 items
    - Letters and obituary notices re: D. B. Jennings death, 1839; 6 items
  - Letters and album, Folder F
    - Lewis B. Jennings' correspondence, 1847-1850; 4 items
    - Annotated album of Genoa to A. G. Jennings from L. B. Jennings, 1852
  - Mary A. Jennings' correspondence, 1840, 1842, n.d.; Folder G; 3 items
  - Letters (unidentified), Folder H; 12 items
  - Calling cards, Folder I; 119 items
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified papers, Folder Jq; 26 items
  - Recipe books, 1832, n.d.; Folder K; 2 items
  - Photo and newspaper clippings, 1800's; Folder L; 10 items
- Box XIII: Letters to Charles B. Jennings, 1885-1912; 8 folders, 147 items
  A partial, more detailed inventory of the letters is available inside the Box.
  - Letters from George E. Hill, 1885-1903; Folders A-C; 40 items
  - Letters from Isaac Jennings, 1885-1886; Folder D; 30 items
  - Letters from S. C. Morehouse, 1904-1912; Folders E-H; 77 items
- Box XIV: Charles B. Jennings papers, 1880-1950; 12 folders, 178 items
  A partial, more detailed inventory is available inside the Box.
  - Incoming correspondence, 1880-1949; Folders A-D; 78 items
  - Admissions exam for Yale and miscellaneous academic papers, 1882-1884, 1907; Folder E; 18 items
  - Sociable Debating Club papers, 1883; Folder F; 4 items
  - Miscellaneous papers, Folder G; 18 items
    - Mary E. Jennings probate papers, 1887, 1892
    - Charles B. Jennings probate papers and estate inventory
    - Deeds from and payments to Mallett & Bennett Seeley re: Easton Mill, library report and bank resolution, 1887, 1900, 1950; 9 items
    - Charles B. Jennings confirmation card, 1879
    - Letter to Betsy, 1901
  - Rye Seminary booklets, 1873, 1929; Folder H
  - Letters to Mrs. Charles B. Jennings from Anne Morehouse in Rosemond, IL, 1912; Folder i; 12 items
  - Letters to Mrs. Charles B. Jennings, 1893, 1915-1916; Folder J; 12 items
  - Invitations to Mr. and Mrs. Charles B. Jennings, 1922-1940; Folder K; 6 items
  - Cards and letters to Charles B. Jennings, 1950; Folder L; 14 items
- Box XV: Charles B. Jennings Yale College papers, 5 folders, 42 items
  A partial, more detailed inventory is available in the Box.
  - Papers, 1883-1897; Folders A & B; 23 items
  - Papers, 1900's; Folders C-E; 19 items
- Box XVI: Sympathy cards and letters, 1944-1954; 8 folders, 245 items
  A more detailed inventory is available inside the Box.
  - Sympathy letters to Charles B. and A. E. Jennings, 1944; Folders A & B; 84 items
  - Sympathy letters and cards to A. E. Jennings, 1950, 1952, 1954; Folders C-H; 157 items
- Box XVII: A. E. Jennings household account books and Christmas lists, 1904-1975; 5 folders, 22 items
  - Account books, 1912-1917, 1922-1937, 1934-1943, 1949; Folder A; 4 items
  - Account books, 1947-1953, 1954-1960; Folder B; 2 items
  - Account books, 1956-1964; Folder C; 7 items
  - Account books, 1964-1968; Flder D; 4 items
  - Accounts books and Christmas lists, 1969-1975, 1904-1940; Folder E; 4 items
- Box XVIII: A. E. Jennings bank and records books, school papers, letters and paper money, 1776-1970; 9 folders, 167 items
  - Bank books, 1903-1926, n.d.; Folder A; 3 items
  - Record book, 1939-1950; Folder B
  - Clippings from record book, 1950-1979; Folder C; 75 items
  - Papers from record book, 1950-1979; Folder D; 32 items
  - Cortland School papers and report cards, 1905-1922; Folder E; 15 items
  - Letters to A. E. Jennings and misc., 1912-1950; Folder F; 41 items
  - Fairfield Garden Club awards and church membership, 1924, 1926; Folder G; 3 items
  - Paper money (Continental Congress note and 5 cent note), 1776, 1863; Folder H; 2 items
  - Clippings re: Ogden House, 1957-1974; Folder I
- Box XIX: Jennings Brothers papers, 1867-1900; 5 folders, 57 items
  - Price lists and catalogues, 1895-1900; Folder A; 25 items
  - Receipt book with revenue stamps, 1869; Folder B; 1 item
  - Articles of agreement, 1870, 1881; Folder C; 5 items
  - Patents, 1867, 1868; Folde D; 7 items
  - Patents other than Jennings Brothers, 1861-1868; Folder E; 19 items
- Box XX: Genealogy, maps and Centennial Committee, 1939, n.d.; 4 folders, 235 items
  - Genealogy, n.d.; Folders A & B; 225 items
  - Maps, Folder C; 5 items
  - Fairfield Centennial Committee, 1939, n.d.; Folder D; 5 items
- Box XXI: Family papers other than Morehouse and Jennings, 1748-1936; 13 folders, 119 items
  - Beers family papers, 1871; Folder A; 7 items
  - Bulkley family papers, 1845-1926; Folder B & C; 28 items
  - Burr family papers, 1827-1875; Folder D; 19 items
  - John H. Glover papers, 1858, 1867; Folder E; 3 items
  - Hyde family papers, 1911, 1923, 1936; Folder F; 3 items
  - Knapp family papers, 1860, 18662; Folder G; 2 items
  - Nichols family papers, 1850; Folder H; 3 items
  - Ogden family papers and deeds, 1749-1855; Folder I
    A detailed list of deeds is available in the folder.
  - Ogden family papers, 1776-1902; Folder J; 30 items
    A detailed list of papers is available in the folder.
  - Osborne family papers, 1840-1842, 1879; Folder K; 4 items
  - Sturgis family papers, 1755, n.d; Folder L; 4 items
  - Misc. family papers, Barlow, Lyon and Perry, 1902, n.d.; Folder M; 5 items
- Box XXII: Fairfield First Church of Christ Congregational papers, 1797-1898; 14 folders, 681 items
  - Sales of church seats, 1821-1856; Folder A; 26 items
  - Sales of church seats, 1878-1879, 1884-1889, 1894-1895; Folder B; 12 items
  - Members' taxes to church, 1852-1879; Folder C; 19 items
  - Church meeting notices, 1840-1880; Folder D; 25 items
  - Church treasurer's report, 1832-1878; Folder E; 38 items
  - Church bills and bills receipted, 1815-1898; Folders F-I; 275 items
  - Church membership withdrawals certificates, 1821-1848; Folder J; 35 items
  - Church miscellaneous papers, 1797-1898; Folders K & L; 78 items
  - Church parsonage bills and bills receipted, 1856-1869; Folder M; 71 items
  - Church parsonage bills and bills receipted, parsonage floor plan, 1870-1896; Folder N; 104 items
- Box XXIII: Fairfield First Church of Christ Congregational papers, 1753-1937; 6 folders, 44 items
  - Account book, 1753-1797; Folder A
  - Account books, 1771-1781, 1881-1882, 1881-1895, 1881-1898; Folder B; 4 items
  - Account books, 1888-1889, 1904-1931, 1924-1937; Folder C; 3 items
  - Account book with loose papers, 1871-1895; Folder D; 22 items
  - Account book with loose papers, 1901-1903; Folder E; 12 items
  - Sabbath school books, 1829-1854, 1863-1865; Folder F; 2 items
- Box XXIV: Fairfield First Church of Christ Congregational papers, 1849-1929; 7 folders, 73 items
  - Church corner stone papers and Bible places by Rev. Lyman H. Atwater, 1849; Folder A; 12 items
  - Pulpit hymnal published 1865, saved from fire 1890, Folder B
  - Building contracts and building committee minutes, 1891-1892; Folder C; 4 items
  - Building account book and bills, 1892; Folder D; 25 items
  - Church silver correspondence, 1908, 1910; Folder E; 11items
  - Sherman property, 1919, 1925, 1929; Folder F; 6 items
  - Church pamphlets and addresses, Folder G; 11 items
- Box XXV: Fairfield First Church of Christ Congregational papers, 4 folders, 42 items
  - Church leaflets, 1960-1969; Folder A; 14 items
  - Cookbooks and plays, Folder B; 6 items
  - Annual report and clippings, 1970-1979; Folder C; 10 items
  - Miscellaneous, Folder D; 12 items
- Box XXVI: Saint Paul's Episcopal Church papers, 1872-1953; 6 folders, 122 items
  - Letters, bills and bills receipted, 1872-1889; Folders A-D; 108 items
  - Account book with loose papers, 1874-1886; Folder E
  - Centennial house tour, 1953; folder F; 1 item
- Box XXVII: Fairfield School District papers, 1851-1881; 12 folders, 140 items
  - Record book of Southport school and diary, 1851-1852, 1863-1892; Folder A; 1 item
  - School district reports, 1868-1869; Folders B & C; 30 items
  - School enumerations, 1869; Folder D; 21 items
  - School district reports, 1870; Folder E; 16 items
  - School enumerations, 1870; Folder F; 15 items
  - School district reports, 1871; Folder G; 14 items
  - School enumerations, 1871; Folder H; 12 items
  - Connecticut school register, 1871; Folder I
  - School district reports, 1872; Folder J; 13 items
  - School enumerations, 1872; Folder K; 12 items
  - School district papers misc., 1871-1881; Folder L; 5 items
- Box XXVIII: Identified photographs, 18 folders, 174 items
  - Thaddeus Burr, Roger and Elizabeth Sherman, Rev. Peter Bulkley, Folder A; 3 items; These are reproductions.
  - Black Rock, Folder B; 1 item
  - Franklin A. Bulkley, Folder C; 1 item
  - Henry Eben Burr, Folder D; 1 item
  - Duck Farm bridge, Folder E; 2 items
  - Fairfield Memorial Library, Folder F; 2 items
  - Fairfield scenes, Folder G; 33 items
  - Fairfield town hall, Folder H; 3 items
  - First Church of Christ, Fairfield, Folder I; 19 items
  - George E. Hill, Folder J; 2 items
  - Elizabeth Hyde, Folder K; 1 item
  - A. E. Jennings, Folder L; 28 items
  - Charles B. Jennings, Folder M; 15 items
  - Charles B. Jennings' home, 1054 Post Rd., Folder N; 13 items
  - Charles B. Jennings' room at Yale and alumni photos, Folder O; 12 items
  - Isaac Jennings, Folder P; 3 items
  - Isaac Jennings' friends, Folder Q; 17 items
  - Isaac Jennings' house, Folder R; 9 items
- Box XXIX: Identified photographs and postcards, 16 folders, 122 items
  - Mary E. Morehouse Jennings, Folder A; 8 items
  - Mary B. Kippen, Folder B; 2 items
  - Large family, Illinois (Wilcox and Hawkes), Folder C; 10 items
  - Mill Plain bridge and drum corps, Folder D; 5 items
  - Samuel and Martha Morehouse, 1890-1910; Folder E; 18 items
  - Old Academy, Folder F; 4 items
  - Old Burying Ground, Folder G; 5 items
  - Perry's mill, Folder H; 1 item
  - Powder House, Folder I; 5 items
  - Round Hill windmill, 1897; Folder J; 3 items
  - Rye Seminary, Rye, NY, Folder K; 10 items
  - Alice Sherwood, Folder L; 1 item
  - Southport (Tide mill and bridges), Folder M; 3 items
  - Wakemen photographs, Folder N; 32 items
  - Westport, CT postcards, Folder O; 8 items
  - Fairfield scenes, Folder P; 9 items
- Box XXX: Photographs of the Child family, 5 folders, 89 items
- Box XXXI: Photo albums-Jennings, Morehouse, Wakeman, 2 items
- Box XXXII: Photographs-Jennings, Morehouse, domestic help
  A further description of the items in this box is available inside the Box.
- Box XXXIII: Photographs-Jennings family
- Box XXXIV: Photographs-Taken while traveling
- Box XXXV: Isaac Jennings account book, includes estate records, 1802-1812, 1819
- Oversize Item A: Plates and photos, 27 items
  - Loose plates from American Family Antiquity by Albert Welles [929.2 J54w]
  - Photographs of Yale Class reunion, 1887; 5 items
  - Photograph of Oliver Jennings
  - Photographs of First Church of Christ, 2 items
  - Photograph of Isaac Jennings' house, 156 Round Hill Rd., 3 items
  - Unidentified photographs, 8 items
- Ovesize Item C: Ambrotypes, tintypes, and daguerreotypes of Carte de visites, 43 items
- Oversize Item E: Architectural drawings of Isaac Jennings' house by William Beer, Architect, Tribune Building in NYC
- Oversize Item F: Tiles a1 and b2-Aaron Arrowsmith's chart of the East India Islands, "additions to 1809"